ED1
What is this? You've got a
huge hole in your window!
That's hardly my fault. I got
attacked by that Lancer guy.
Wait. You fought him on your
own before you summoned Saber?
Not really. He
just kicked my butt.
Not even trying to make
yourself sound good?
I see. When it comes to you,
what you see really is what you get.
- Minuten vor Schweißen.
- Minutes before welding.
Tohsaka...
You really are a mage, huh?
You're one too, aren't you?
Not really. I can't
do anything like this.
What do you mean, you can't?
Working with glass is the
most basic of the basics.
I don't know any of these
"basics" or "fundamentals."
Honestly, how did someone like
you manage to summon Saber?
Well, whatever.
First things first, I need
to repay you for earlier.
In the face of absolute despair
You don't have any idea what
you're caught up in, do you?
To be blunt, you've
been chosen as a Master.
Have you noticed a brand
somewhere on your body?
A brand?
She is referring to the
Command Spells, Shirou.
O-Oh, these?
Yes. Those symbolize
your status as a Master.
They're also spells
which bind your Servant.
So as long as you have those,
you can control your Servant.
What do you mean,
as long as I have them?
Command Spells
are inviolable orders.
They force your Servant's obedience,
even if it means bending them to your will.
Saber broke off her
attack earlier, remember?
However, you only get three such
orders, so try not to waste them.
If you use them all, you'll probably be
killed, so I suggest you exercise caution.
I'll be killed?
That's right.
The Holy Grail War is based around
Masters defeating other Masters.
Whichever Master prevails
over the other six will
win the Holy Grail,
which can grant any wish.
Hey, hold on a second. What
do you mean by "Holy Grail"?
To cut a long story short,
you've been dragged into a ritual.
One called the Holy Grail
War, fought by seven Masters...
a battle to the death
between mages.
What the hell are
you talking about?
I'm simply laying out the facts.
Besides, it should be obvious
even to you at this point.
After all, a Servant nearly
killed you not once but twice.
Convinced yet?
I was also chosen as a Master.
Think of your Servant as
a familiar, granted to you
by the Grail to help you
win the Holy Grail War.
She doesn't look much
like a familiar to me.
Of course not.
Though they're technically
classed as familiars,
Servants are actually superhuman
beings—heroes from the past.
Heroes from the past?
Saber too?
That's right.
Servants are heroes
summoned from legends...
be they ancient or modern—into
our time and given physical forms.
It's the Master's
role to summon them,
upon which they are made manifest
through a phenomenon of the Grail.
Basically, a Servant is
always with you in spirit form.
And should the need arise, you
can make them materialize and fight.
So that guy in red can transform at
will between spirit and physical form?
That's Archer.
I'm having him keep watch
outside for the time being.
Do you understand
everything so far?
The individual words, sure.
If you want a more
detailed explanation, you
should talk to the man
who oversees the Grail War.
All I can tell you
is that you have no
choice but to fight,
and that Servants are powerful
familiars, so you should use yours well.
Now, then.
From what Emiya-kun has said,
I gather that you're in an
incomplete state, Saber?
Yes.
As you say, I am not
at full fighting strength.
Shirou is not a
full-fledged Master,
so even replenishing my
mana is likely to be difficult.
That's surprising.
Hey, what are you two
talking about, Tohsaka?
Servants maintain their existence
here with mana supplied by their Masters.
But because you're a novice, she
can't get mana from you directly,
which will make
things difficult.
Would you like some, Emiya-kun?
I'm good.
I have to admit, I didn't expect
you to be so forthcoming with me.
You'd already realized something was wrong,
so there was no point in concealing it.
Given that, I felt revealing our
hand to an enemy such as yourself
could help Shirou better
understand our situation.
Her disposition's perfect, too.
Damn it, that makes it
even more of a waste!
If I were Saber's Master, this
war would be as good as won!
Hey, are you saying
I'm not worthy of her?
Of course I am, you hack!
Okay, shall we go?
Go? Where?
To see the man who knows
all about the Holy Grail War.
You want to know what
all this is for, don't you?
Of course.
It's kind of late, though.
What? Not interested after all?
Well, it's your call.
What about you, Saber?
Leave Saber out of this!
Don't try to strong-arm her.
Oh, so you do
think like a Master.
You don't want me
talking to Saber?
Why should I care?
Damn, I'm starting to feel like
something is wrong with her.
I mean, Saber's a hero
from the past, right?
She won't be able to make
sense of the modern world.
That isn't true, Shirou.
Servants adapt to whatever
era they find themselves in.
As such, I am quite
familiar with this time.
You're familiar with it? Really?
Of course.
This is also not the first time I
have been summoned to this era.
No way! What are the odds?
Well? Where are we going?
The church in Shinto.
What else can we do?
She can't dematerialize.
It beats having her walk
around with her armor on display.
Hey, are you planning to
walk all the way to the next city?
I am.
You know it's been
dangerous out lately, right?
I can't guarantee your
safety if things go south.
Relax.
You may be forgetting, but Saber
over there is ridiculously strong.
Master of Archer.
Just call me Rin.
In that case, Rin. What was
Shirou trying to say earlier?
I am unable to comprehend it.
Perhaps it was out of
a major misconception,
or just sheer stupidity, but...
He was saying that he'll leap
to our rescue if we get attacked.
But... Shirou is my Master.
Is that not a
reversal of our roles?
He's probably not
thinking that way at all.
He couldn't care less about
Masters, Servants, or anything like that.
What's that supposed to mean?
Why do you suppose
Saber won't come in with us?
She said she's been in
this time period before.
So maybe something happened
between her and the phony priest here.
Tohsaka, what kind
of guy is this priest?
He used to be my father's pupil.
After Father died, he
became my guardian.
He and Father taught
me everything I know.
Wait, so this priest
is also a mage?
That's right.
He's a certified
phony, that priest.
You've accepted none
of my prior invitations,
but here you are now
with an unusual guest.
I take it this means
he is the seventh,
Rin?
I am Kotomine Kirei.
What is your name,
seventh Master?
Emiya Shirou.
Emiya?
Then, Emiya Shirou, can I assume you
are the Master of the Saber-class Servant?
Yeah, I made a
contract with Saber,
but this stuff about Masters and the
Holy Grail War is all nonsense to me.
If a Master is supposed
to be a proper mage,
you really ought to
pick someone else.
I see.
This is serious indeed.
You'll need to start
from square one with him.
Very well.
This is the first time you have
ever sought my assistance.
Emiya Shirou,
the status of Master
cannot be yielded to another.
And, once conferred, it is not a thing
from which one can simply walk away.
Being a Master is a trial you
have been chosen to undergo.
You will not be freed from that
ordeal until you win the Grail.
Emiya Shirou, this battle
you've found yourself
caught up in is called
the Holy Grail War.
Some nonsense about seven
Masters fighting to the death, right?
It is a ritual meant to select the
one who is worthy to hold the Grail.
You keep talking about
this "Holy Grail", but
you don't mean the
actual Holy Grail, do you?
The Grail that appears in
this town is the genuine article.
For proof, one need look no further
than the unrivaled miracle of the Servants.
A Holy Grail capable of this can
surely grant its holder limitless power.
In the face of such a fact, the
item's "authenticity" is irrelevant.
Then why force people to go
through this Holy Grail War thing?
If it's that powerful,
why not just share it?
A reasonable suggestion, but
only one may claim the Grail.
We did not make that decision.
Rather, the Grail itself decided it.
The Grail decided it?
This is all the work
of the Grail itself.
It selects its one true owner by
having the Masters fight to win it.
That is the Holy Grail War.
I'm still not convinced.
Even if only one can be chosen,
I don't like the idea that that
person has to kill the other Masters.
Hold on.
We don't have to kill
each other, Emiya-kun.
No, it is a fight to the death.
Hush, Kirei!
Listen, the Holy Grail that appears
in this city is a spiritual object.
And since it's spiritual,
we can't touch it.
Do you see where I'm going?
Right.
The point of the Holy Grail War is to
get rid of all the other Masters' Servants.
Which means that there is no rule stating
that you have to kill the other Masters.
Emiya Shirou, if I may ask...
Do you think that you could
defeat your own Servant?
Servants are difficult to defeat,
even if you have a Servant yourself.
So what to do?
The answer is simple, is it not?
No matter how
powerful the Servant,
if its Master is killed,
the Servant will vanish.
In which case...
Killing the Master
is the quickest way.
Exactly.
But what about the opposite case? What
if a Master's Servant is destroyed first?
Only Servants can
touch the Grail, right?
That implies that a Master who's lost
their Servant no longer has any value.
No, as long as their Command Spells
exist, so do their rights as a Master.
So, if there were a Servant that had
lost its Master and had nowhere to go,
it would still have a
chance to rejoin the battle.
It is for that reason that
Masters kill other Masters.
Then what if I used up all my
Command Spells right now?
Wait, that's...
True, you would relinquish
your rights as a Master.
Although I cannot imagine
a mage using magic as
powerful as a Command
Spell in so wasteful a manner.
Any such mage could not
even be called incompetent...
they would be no
more than a coward.
Have I convinced you?
Then let us go back to the
beginning, Emiya Shirou.
If you wish to forfeit your
status as Master, then so be it.
Simply use up your Command Spells
and break your contract with Saber.
If you do so, I shall guarantee your
safety until the Holy Grail War's end.
Why would I need you
to guarantee my safety?
I was dispatched here to oversee
the cycle of Holy Grail Wars.
Safeguarding mages that are no longer
Masters is the overseer's top priority.
"Cycle"?
Hang on...
The Holy Grail War
didn't begin just now?
This is the fifth such war.
The previous one was ten years
ago, making this the shortest cycle yet.
This has happened
four times before?
Yes.
With each cycle, the Holy Grail
War has only grown more brutal.
Driven by their desires, Masters have
engaged in indiscriminate slaughter.
Indiscriminate slaughter...
Then what would happen if
the Grail fell into evil hands?
It is beyond our means to stop
one whom the Grail has chosen.
After all, it is an omnipotent,
wish-granting chalice.
If you do not wish that to happen,
Emiya Shirou, win it yourself.
At the very least, if you win, it will
not go to an indiscriminate killer, yes?
I have no reason to fight.
So you have no interest in
what the Grail's holder does,
no matter what atrocities
may be wrought?
That's not...
If you have no
reason to fight, so be it.
I take it the events of ten
years ago do not concern you?
Ten years ago?
Indeed.
At the end of the previous Grail War,
an unworthy Master touched the Grail.
I know not of what
that Master wished.
All we know is the
resultant disaster.
Wait a minute.
Are you saying...
I am.
The Shinto fire, whose cause
remains officially unknown,
was the result of the
last Holy Grail War.
Emiya-kun!
You said that this
is the fifth one, right?
Has anyone ever
won the Grail, then?
One man did indeed
hold the Grail, albeit briefly.
What happened to him?
Nothing.
That Grail did not
achieve completion.
The result of a foolish man letting
sentiment get the better of him.
Simply causing the
Grail to appear is trivial.
Once the seven Servants are
gathered, the Grail will appear in time.
As Rin says, it is not necessary
to slay the other Masters.
But unless you do so, the
Grail will never be complete.
It chooses the Master
who is worthy of it.
That is why this man, who
avoided fighting, did not win the Grail.
In other words,
obtaining the Grail is
meaningless unless you
settle things with
the other Masters first.
In the last war, the
Master who was first to
get his hands on the
Grail was a naïve fool.
That is all I have to say.
Will you participate
in the Holy Grail War?
Make your decision,
Emiya Shirou.
Rejoice, boy.
Your wish will
finally come true.
Surely you've realized.
Your wish cannot come true
without a clear and distinct evil.
Though you may refuse to
admit it, a champion of justice
must have an evil to defeat.
Shirou, have you concluded
your business here?
Yeah.
And?
I have decided to
fight as a Master.
Will you agree to me
as your Master, Saber?
My agreement is irrelevant.
You have been my
Master from the very start.
Did I not swear that my
body would be your blade?
Right, in that case...
I will be your Master.
I'll be counting on you, Saber.
What? We aren't
supposed to shake hands?
It isn't that.
I was simply taken by surprise.
Allow me to renew my vow.
So long as the Command Spells are
on your body, I shall serve as your blade.
If the Holy Grail War was the
cause of the fire ten years ago,
I won't let something like
that ever happen again.
Tohsaka?
No offense, but you should
go home on your own.
Huh?
I brought you here because you
weren't officially my enemy yet.
But now, you're a
fellow Master, Emiya-kun.
I have no intention of
fighting you, Tohsaka.
I should have known.
Jeez, why did I even
bother bringing you here?
Rin.
What?
If an easily slain enemy presents itself,
we'd be remiss not to take advantage.
You don't have to tell me that.
If you agree, then act.
Or what?
Will you take pity
on that boy again?
Don't tell me you have feel...
O-Of course not!
I just, well...
I owe him, you know?
And I can't fight with a clear
conscience until I've repaid him.
Complicating things again.
In that case, send for me when
you have repaid this debt of yours.
Tohsaka? By
"debt", do you mean...
Yes.
Regardless of why you did it, you
used a Command Spell to stop Saber.
So I have to go easy on
you to balance the scales.
You get hung up on the
weirdest things, Tohsaka.
I know that. But
I have no choice.
I hate being
indebted to someone.
You're a good
person, aren't you?
Flattery won't make
me go any easier on you!
I know. But I don't want us
to be enemies if I can help it.
I like people like you.
See you around.
So, are you done chatting?
Berserker?
Okay, I'll kill you now.
Is he immortal?
Shirou, get back!
Don't you get that
you're just in the way?
Didn't we just decide that
we would fight together?!
A disgraceful hind
deserves to be skewered.